<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personalization Team on The Personalization Podcast</title>
    <link>http://personalizationpodcast.com/tags/personalization-team/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personalization Team on The Personalization Podcast</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2016 20:21:07 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://personalizationpodcast.com/tags/personalization-team/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 7: Agile Story Time</title>
      <link>http://personalizationpodcast.com/post/episode-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2016 20:21:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://personalizationpodcast.com/post/episode-7/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;166&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/247755914&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;As a Marketer, I want to Personalize my site, so that I can better engage with my audience.&amp;rdquo; That&amp;rsquo;s an example of
how I might write an Agile Story about Personalization. In this episode we discuss the usefulness of stories in the
Agile process and also explore their direct relevance to helping us think about the right way to personalize by
focussing on the &amp;ldquo;who&amp;rdquo; and the &amp;ldquo;why&amp;rdquo; of what we&amp;rsquo;re doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-the-news:1520420b25182acb3bb29f38c6abc31d&#34;&gt;In the News&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;personalization-paradox-http-www-wunderman-emea-com-5-pointers-to-tackle-the-triple-personalization-paradox:1520420b25182acb3bb29f38c6abc31d&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wunderman-emea.com/5-pointers-to-tackle-the-triple-personalization-paradox&#34;&gt;Personalization Paradox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paradox #1. While paramount to cure the sheer saturation of inboxes and social feeds — see, for example, the Twitterverse’s recent ‘algorithm anxiety’ — &lt;strong&gt;personalization requires content in an even more vast variety to cater for individual needs and tastes.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paradox #2. The closer marketers get, it seems, the more likely they are to miss the mark: &lt;strong&gt;success recipes to ensure messages fall on the right ears at the right time definitely grow longer as conversations get more intimate.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paradox #3. Consumers seem to suffer from some sort of Catullus 85 Complex when it comes to personalization: they hate and they love personalization to a very similar extent: &lt;strong&gt;“39% of consumers say they get frustrated when retailers don’t offer personalized recommendations; 38% say the same about personalized offers.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personalization at its best is a problem solver, a relevant, tailored service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Content is probably the most often overlooked component of the “unified data ecosystem” enabling personalization.
A vital key to personalization success is, nonetheless, to be found in your CMS. If your messages are to be tailored
and meaningful in a one-to-one conversation, you are going to need a massive amount of them and they’ll have to
be tagged / calendared ex-ten-sive-ly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-your-organization-is-approaching-personalization-all-wrong-http-blogs-forrester-com-fiona-adler-16-01-12-why-your-organization-is-approaching-personalization-wrong:1520420b25182acb3bb29f38c6abc31d&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.forrester.com/fiona_adler/16-01-12-why_your_organization_is_approaching_personalization_wrong&#34;&gt;Why Your Organization is Approaching Personalization All Wrong&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;by Fiona Adler&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s in a name? Personalization vs. Individualization vs. Contextualization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ron Rogowski has &lt;a href=&#34;https://uxmag.com/articles/contextualization-is-the-key-to-delivering-powerful-personalized-digital-experiences&#34;&gt;written about contextualization vs. personalization&lt;/a&gt; as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firms that succeed with personalization are proactive and intentional about it.
They treat personalization as an enabler of better interactions from the
customers’ view across their journeys. Rather than contemplating, &amp;ldquo;How can
my organization implement personalization?&amp;rdquo; they ask, &amp;ldquo;What tasks and goals
are users trying to accomplish, and how can personalization enable users to
more seamlessly accomplish those?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;agile-stories:1520420b25182acb3bb29f38c6abc31d&#34;&gt;Agile Stories&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Format:&lt;/em&gt;
- Who - &amp;ldquo;As a&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;
- What - &amp;ldquo;I want&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;
- Why - &amp;ldquo;So that&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;As a shopper, I want to see product prices clearly labeled, so that I can find
something I know     is in my budget before I go to checkout.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;As a parent, I want my child to go to bed at night, so that I can relax.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;As a child, I want to wake up early in the morning, so that I can play.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;agile-personalization-stories:1520420b25182acb3bb29f38c6abc31d&#34;&gt;Agile Personalization Stories&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When writing stories for personalization, check the who and why closely. I can
write a story like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;As a Return Visitor, I want to see a message that says &amp;lsquo;welcome back!&amp;rsquo; so that
I can feel more appreciated.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watch out though. Do you actually know that this is the case? Do your return
visitors really want to be recognized as returning visitors? What if they feel
creeped out that you&amp;rsquo;re tracking them? This is a real concern and something that
may need to be addressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how do you deal with this? Research! If you don&amp;rsquo;t know for sure if your story
is true, then consider a more accurate story:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;As a Marketer, I want to test putting a &amp;lsquo;welcome back&amp;rsquo; message on the
home page for return visitors, so that I can determine whether they will (buy more,
stay longer, etc..)&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a research focussed story as opposed to a &amp;ldquo;just do it&amp;rdquo; story and it much
more accurately reflects our reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What about the &amp;ldquo;So What?&amp;rdquo; We can and will dedicate a few future episodes to talking
about Goal tracking and measurement, but this is where you can easily identify
the metric that you are trying to effect from creating this personalized experience.
This idea is absolutely critical, because if you&amp;rsquo;re not measuring something that
impacts your bottom line, then you have no idea whether your effort is paying
off or not. Always be very clear about what you&amp;rsquo;re measuring and why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice that the story format doesn&amp;rsquo;t address &amp;ldquo;how&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;when&amp;rdquo;. &amp;ldquo;How&amp;rdquo; should be
discussed, but when you&amp;rsquo;re trying to determine what will have the most effect
on your business or organization, asking who? what? and why? are your best
places to start.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>