<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on The Personalization Podcast</title>
    <link>http://personalizationpodcast.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on The Personalization Podcast</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://personalizationpodcast.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 10: Customer Experience Fundamentals with Melanie Poitras</title>
      <link>http://personalizationpodcast.com/post/episode-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://personalizationpodcast.com/post/episode-10/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;166&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/252836314&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building Customer Experience has many challenges. Content Strategy, measurement of business goals and personalizations. I sit down in this episode with Melanie Poitras, a friend and colleague who works with Acquia&amp;rsquo;s customers to help define and plan their customer experience strategy, often leading up to implementing Personalization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-s-news-to-me:6967be25898c1100bccbb0031f0a4e60&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s News to Me&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;google-analytics-360-suite-https-www-google-com-analytics-360-suite-modal-active-none:6967be25898c1100bccbb0031f0a4e60&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/analytics/360-suite/#?modal_active=none&#34;&gt;Google Analytics 360 Suite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there&amp;rsquo;s one thing that matters this week, it&amp;rsquo;s Google&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://analytics.blogspot.com/2016/03/introducing-google-analytics-360-suite.html&#34;&gt;announcement of Analytics 360&lt;/a&gt;. This includes 6 different products, 4 of which are brand new:
- Google Audience Center 360 (beta)
- Google Optimize 360 (beta)
- Google Data Studio 360 (beta)
- Google Tag Manager 360
- Google Analytics 360 (formerly GA Premium)
- Google Attribution 360 (formerly Adometry)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know less than we&amp;rsquo;d like at this point, but this is something I&amp;rsquo;ll be following and reporting on as I learn more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;digital-marketing-trends-does-personalization-matter-anymore-http-www-skyword-com-contentstandard-news-digital-marketing-trends-does-personalization-matter-anymore-platform-hootsuite:6967be25898c1100bccbb0031f0a4e60&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.skyword.com/contentstandard/news/digital-marketing-trends-does-personalization-matter-anymore/?platform=hootsuite&#34;&gt;Digital Marketing Trends: Does Personalization Matter Anymore?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.skyword.com/contentstandard/author/sw-24549/&#34;&gt;Jonathan Crowl&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;gt; Personalization is still very important, if only to keep pace with the rest of the industry. But to truly champion personalization in your digital marketing strategy, brands must take extra steps to deliver a user experience that is genuinely tailored at the individual level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later he continues:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personalization is cutthroat among brands. There is enormous value in demonstrating to consumers that you know them and understand their needs better than anyone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IBM’s Watson solution can reference personality profiles to match their communication style and tone with the type of person being addressed. It can differentiate, as an example, between a retiree and a Millennial, and provide the tone that each group would likely prefer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such a solution would be costly and complex to implement, but the value can’t be understated. While such solutions aren’t ready for mass distribution, they highlight the direction brands are going: Personalization knows no bounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;email-marketing-in-2020-https-litmus-com-lp-email-marketing-in-2020:6967be25898c1100bccbb0031f0a4e60&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://litmus.com/lp/email-marketing-in-2020&#34;&gt;Email Marketing in 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great resource about the future of Email Marketing .. hint: Personalization is a big part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One interesting note is that 66% of respondents to a survey say that machine learning, AI and predictive software will determine the majority of the content in marketing emails over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;interview-with-melanie-poitras:6967be25898c1100bccbb0031f0a4e60&#34;&gt;Interview with Melanie Poitras&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customer Experience has several pillars, one of which is Personalization. I had the privilege of sitting down with Melanie who talks and thinks about this stuff all day long. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 9: What&#39;s in a name?</title>
      <link>http://personalizationpodcast.com/post/episode-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://personalizationpodcast.com/post/episode-9/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;166&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/250078181&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s in a name? A rose by any other name would smell as sweet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; Juliet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does it matter what we call &amp;ldquo;Personalization&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are only two hard things in Computer Science: cache invalidation and naming things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; Phil Karlton&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it does, and the industry is struggling. Today I heard a new proposal, &amp;ldquo;Personification&amp;rdquo;, which would be used to address some level of privacy concerns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we need is a Taxonomy for Personalization, and it turns out I&amp;rsquo;m not the first person to think that. So that&amp;rsquo;s what this episode is all about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-s-news-to-me:48a625d4323d5e3a4c2d0b872d846889&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s News to Me&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;content-personalization-webinar:48a625d4323d5e3a4c2d0b872d846889&#34;&gt;Content Personalization Webinar&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had the privilege of speaking on an online &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bigmarker.com/digitaled/How-to-Personalize-Your-Content-for-Better-Engagement?bmid=09628cbb17ae&#34;&gt;panel about content personalization&lt;/a&gt; yesterday. I was joined by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sarakeiko&#34;&gt;Sara Sarasohn from NPR&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/eui-hong-sam-han-ab43753&#34;&gt;Sam Han&lt;/a&gt; from the Washington Post, both of whose organizations are doing very interesting things around content recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;let-s-get-personal-content-experts-share-their-advice:48a625d4323d5e3a4c2d0b872d846889&#34;&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s Get Personal: Content Experts Share Their Advice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/DomNicastro&#34;&gt;Dom Nicastro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cmswire.com/digital-experience/lets-get-personal-content-experts-share-their-advice/&#34;&gt;article on CMS Wire&lt;/a&gt;, Dom writes a clear and open piece about the challenges surrounding personalization. He&amp;rsquo;s embarking on a series that I&amp;rsquo;ll be following where he talks with organizations who are implementing personalization with various technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dom writes:
&amp;gt; Talk to any personalization technology vendor and chances are you&amp;rsquo;ll hear a beguiling tale of true one-to-one customer experiences made possible by their product’s uncanny ability to serve up the right content to the right person through the right channel at the right time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a seductive vision: Just rev up the personalization engine and voilà, you’ve activated your express pass to conversion and traffic heaven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, if you&amp;rsquo;ve followed this podcast so far, you know that&amp;rsquo;s not my view, and we&amp;rsquo;ve talked about the amount of work involved in getting this stuff done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dom also writes that:
&amp;gt; The privacy implications of personalization weigh heavy on marketers as well.
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt; Andrew Frank, research vice president and distinguished analyst at Gartner, advocates for the idea of “personification” over “personalization.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, another name .. what&amp;rsquo;s going to be? contextualization? individualization? personification? segmentation? how about adaptation? Let&amp;rsquo;s explore some more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-should-we-call-this-stuff:48a625d4323d5e3a4c2d0b872d846889&#34;&gt;What should we call this stuff?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Markus Weinmann, Christoph Schneider, Susanne Robra-Bissantz from the University of Braunschweig in Germany and the City University of Hong Kong addressed this question in 2013 in a paper titled &lt;a href=&#34;http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1447&amp;amp;context=amcis2013&#34;&gt;A Taxonomy of Web Personalization&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They propose breaking the concept of Web Personalization into two primary areas and seven sub-areas, with a further breakdown within these seven that looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://personalizationpodcast.com/images/personalization_taxonomy.png&#34; alt=&#34;Web Personalization Taxonomy&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, a &lt;a href=&#34;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2725251&#34;&gt;recent paper on Email personalization&lt;/a&gt; introduces the notion of Non-Informative Content. In other words, the use of a name or company in an email. Of note, they found that &amp;ldquo;adding the name of the message recipient to the email&amp;rsquo;s subject-line increases the probability of the recipient opening it by 20%, which translates to an increase in sales leads by 31% and a reduction in the number of individuals unsubscribing from the email campaign by 17%.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a definition perspective, I&amp;rsquo;ve seen this type of personalization decried recently, but more importantly I&amp;rsquo;ve seen new terms introduced to differentiate other types of personalization. However, from the research above, I think we can safely call this &amp;ldquo;non-informative individual static content, driven by explicit, long-term user data.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Too much of a mouthful? I&amp;rsquo;d say so. I think I&amp;rsquo;m not done with this topic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 8: Context, Context, Context</title>
      <link>http://personalizationpodcast.com/post/episode-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2016 12:21:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://personalizationpodcast.com/post/episode-8/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;context-context-context:86495ce0bd02ab48a50c4325d0c82ced&#34;&gt;Context, Context, Context&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;166&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/248948406&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Content is King, then Context is Queen. Personalization is all about matching
the right content or messaging to the right person, and doing that means you need
to know something about who that person is. In fact, the more you know, the more
likely you are to be successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s not to say that all context is created equal though. Depending on your
organization and your audience, different pieces of information may be critical
or close to meaningless. As a simple example, a retailer may be heavily effected
by a customer&amp;rsquo;s local weather. Cold and rainy, you may need a rain coat. Warm and
Sunny? Time for the beach!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s episode is all about cataloging the &lt;em&gt;kinds of things&lt;/em&gt; that we can know
about the consumers of our digital experiences. The list is quite broad and it
will range from the fairly straight forward and obvious, into perhaps surprising
and sometimes creepy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But first, let&amp;rsquo;s look at the news to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-s-news-to-me:86495ce0bd02ab48a50c4325d0c82ced&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s News to Me&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;etail-west-and-browser-push-notifications:86495ce0bd02ab48a50c4325d0c82ced&#34;&gt;eTail West and Browser Push Notifications&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personalization has been an important strategy for retailers longer than for anyone else. In many ways, Amazon was the original pioneer of personalization with their early product recommendations, and many sellers and personalization vendors have latched onto that idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, &lt;a href=&#34;http://etailwest.wbresearch.com/&#34;&gt;eTail West&lt;/a&gt; is just wrapping up this week, and many sessions focussed on data, omni-channel, personalization and related topics. Before looking at an interesting case study though, I came across a request on eTail&amp;rsquo;s website to subscribe for push notifications. The only place I&amp;rsquo;d seen this before was Facebook, but in case you didn&amp;rsquo;t know, it&amp;rsquo;s now possible to send push notifications directly through a browser. This has generally just been the realm of mobile applications, so this opens up some interesting doors for marketers, though I&amp;rsquo;m not convinced it will really catch on yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, I signed up for the same vendor eTail is using, which is called &lt;a href=&#34;https://pushcrew.com/&#34;&gt;PushCrew&lt;/a&gt;, and have put it up on personalizationpodcast.com at least temporarily to try it out. You can go there and have a look if you&amp;rsquo;re interested. I don&amp;rsquo;t see any capabilities for targeting or personalizing push notifications at the moment, but clearly it would be possible to do this and may be of great interest to some of you out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-sephora-pairs-individual-loyalty-data-to-optimize-segmentation-http-www-luxurydaily-com-how-sephora-pairs-individual-loyalty-data-to-optimize-segmentation:86495ce0bd02ab48a50c4325d0c82ced&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.luxurydaily.com/how-sephora-pairs-individual-loyalty-data-to-optimize-segmentation/&#34;&gt;How Sephora pairs individual, loyalty data to optimize segmentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By Alex Samuely&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“[Data] is kind of a currency to us,” said Angel Singh, director of product
analytics and optimization at Sephora. “We have a lot of data on our clients
and we’re trying to figure out how to leverage it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data is imperative when it comes to pinpointing how best to target consumers, since many of them complete shopping journeys across multiple devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When we think about our clients, we know that they don’t just go into the store and buy something,” Ms. Singh said. “There is a journey.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twenty-three percent of shoppers compare prices on mobile while standing in-store and before going to a bricks-and-mortar location. Additionally, 24 percent engage with a retail app each week, leaving a prime opportunity for marketers to connect with loyal customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sephora has extended its omnichannel reach to include optimized emails, a new subscription box, a mobile app and mobile Web site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The brand also offers a popular loyalty program, Beauty Insider, which rewards users with points for each dollar spent. Points can then be redeemed for sample-size products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we come to the clincher:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sephora is focusing on digging up real-time data, which has previously proven to be a trickier process due to silos. Having access to individual data would help the brand – as well as in-store associates – give shoppers a personalized experience based on their &lt;em&gt;skin types, beauty regimes and past purchases.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We want to recognize everybody,” Ms. Singh said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pull that quote specifically because it captures the point of this episode: Context. Sephora wants to know who people are, and for them that means some very specific things. For your organization, it will certainly be different, but narrowing down which variables matter is the key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;all-about-context:86495ce0bd02ab48a50c4325d0c82ced&#34;&gt;All about Context&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what can you know about your visitors? It turns out that it&amp;rsquo;s really quite a lot. We&amp;rsquo;re going to start by looking at the raw materials, and work outward to see what can be learned based on that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, let&amp;rsquo;s start with a simple HTTP header which may look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;GET /tutorials/other/top-20-mysql-best-practices/ HTTP/1.1
Host: net.tutsplus.com
User-Agent: Mozilla/5.0 (Windows; U; Windows NT 6.1; en-US; rv:1.9.1.5) Gecko/20091102 Firefox/3.5.5 (.NET CLR 3.5.30729)
Accept: text/html,application/xhtml+xml,application/xml;q=0.9,*/*;q=0.8
Accept-Language: en-us,en;q=0.5
Accept-Encoding: gzip,deflate
Accept-Charset: ISO-8859-1,utf-8;q=0.7,*;q=0.7
Referer: https://www.google.com
Keep-Alive: 300
Connection: keep-alive
Cookie: PHPSESSID=r2t5uvjq435r4q7ib3vtdjq120
Pragma: no-cache
Cache-Control: no-cache
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(source: &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.tutsplus.com/tutorials/http-headers-for-dummies--net-8039&#34;&gt;tutsplus.com tutorial&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From this very simple request header, the spec for which was last edited in 1994, we can learn an awful lot:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;user-agent:86495ce0bd02ab48a50c4325d0c82ced&#34;&gt;User Agent&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This short line of text can be hard to read, but thankfully others have done the hard work of being able to do this, and by running this text through various services such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://uadetector.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;UA Detector&lt;/a&gt;, we can learn things like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browser Version&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Device&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Operating System&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;accept-language:86495ce0bd02ab48a50c4325d0c82ced&#34;&gt;Accept-Language&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What language has the visitor set their browser for? This is a great source of information for what they may prefer and allows you to give them content in that language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;referrer:86495ce0bd02ab48a50c4325d0c82ced&#34;&gt;Referrer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where did they come from? Search Engine? Social Media? Another page on your site? An Ad?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of the page they came from, you can also look at parameters in the url such as Campaign and Source, which are often used by analytics, but can also be used for personalization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;cookies:86495ce0bd02ab48a50c4325d0c82ced&#34;&gt;Cookies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First and 3rd party cookies are also passed in here. Cookies are how the browser and the server maintain &amp;ldquo;state&amp;rdquo;, which means that the server can recognize the same person from page to page. This becomes incredibly important in a moment when we talk about behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ip-address:86495ce0bd02ab48a50c4325d0c82ced&#34;&gt;IP address&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While not always in the headers, we have IP addresses available from the request itself. While the IP Address itself may look like just numbers, we can use it to infer, with relatively good accuracy, the geographic location of the visitor using a database such as the one from Maxmind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.maxmind.com/en/locate-my-ip-address&#34;&gt;test it for yourself to see how it does&lt;/a&gt;. For me it nailed my postal code, city and state. It also returned a latitude and longitude, but missed me by about 5 miles. This is because it&amp;rsquo;s the lat/long for the zip code and no closer, so you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t expect huge precision from this method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other services, such as &lt;a href=&#34;demandbase.com&#34;&gt;Demandbase&lt;/a&gt; build databases of IP addresses for organizations and can determine what company is viewing this page, giving you access to information like Company Name, company size, industry, number of employees and more. This &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt; for B2B companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;geography:86495ce0bd02ab48a50c4325d0c82ced&#34;&gt;Geography&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of geolocation, we can also ask the visitor to share their more precise location. This is often done in mobile applications, but can be done on the desktop as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;past-behavior:86495ce0bd02ab48a50c4325d0c82ced&#34;&gt;Past Behavior&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By keeping track of who we&amp;rsquo;ve seen and what they did, now we can build up a picture of who this person is and what they&amp;rsquo;re really looking for. This may well be the holy grail of context for the majority of organizations, but is also considerably more difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Future episodes will discuss machine learning and how this can be applied, but simpler rules based approaches can also be extremely valuable. For example, if a visitor has already bought one product, you can stop showing them that product and show others that are of interest. If they&amp;rsquo;ve spent most of their time on a particular topic on a news site, you might show them more news from that subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-if-cookies-get-cleared:86495ce0bd02ab48a50c4325d0c82ced&#34;&gt;What if Cookies get cleared?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually if someone clears their cookies, if they come to your site again they will look like a brand new user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A variety of technology exists to try to get around this, generally referred to as &amp;ldquo;device fingerprinting&amp;rdquo;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Device_fingerprint&#34;&gt;The Wikipedia page for Device Fingerprinting&lt;/a&gt; does a good job of explaining what it is and the privacy violation risks. That&amp;rsquo;s going to be a topic of a future episode, but for the time being, think twice before doing something like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ask-them-questions:86495ce0bd02ab48a50c4325d0c82ced&#34;&gt;Ask them questions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything above is basically &amp;ldquo;inferred&amp;rdquo; information from what you see a visitor do. You can also just ask them. This is generally done when a user registers for a site and needs to fill in things like name, email address, age, etc. You can also employ the technique of &amp;ldquo;progressive profiling&amp;rdquo;, which means you ask for a little more information each time. LinkedIn is very good at this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also effectively ask questions without requiring a log in. One great example is by providing links in a navigation structure which request that someone identify which type of customer they are. This can then be captured and as long as you still have that visitor cookied, you can remember their selection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;behavior-off-site:86495ce0bd02ab48a50c4325d0c82ced&#34;&gt;Behavior Off-site&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;3rd-party-cookies:86495ce0bd02ab48a50c4325d0c82ced&#34;&gt;3rd Party Cookies&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.oracle.com/cloud/latest/marketingcs_gs/OMCDA/pdf/Misc/bluekai-little-blue-book.pdf&#34;&gt;Little Blue Book&lt;/a&gt; provides an extensive encylopedia of data sources that can be tapped into, largely focussed on 3rd party advertising cookies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These can be great, but beward 3rd party cookie decline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;social-mining:86495ce0bd02ab48a50c4325d0c82ced&#34;&gt;Social Mining&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example company is &lt;a href=&#34;clearbit.com&#34;&gt;Clearbit&lt;/a&gt;. Go there and type in your email address and see what you get. For me it accurately nailed my website, company, twitter handle, as well as information about my company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://personalizationpodcast.com/images/clearbit.png&#34; alt=&#34;Clearbit Data Lookup&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s more, from knowing my twitter handle, one could go and look at my past tweets, who I follow, what I like and dislike (at least, what I&amp;rsquo;ve shared on twitter.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This whole area of social mining is a huge field and there&amp;rsquo;s much more depth possible there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;social-sign-on:86495ce0bd02ab48a50c4325d0c82ced&#34;&gt;Social Sign-on&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides the public facing data available from sites like Facebook and Twitter, if you ask a customer to sign on using a social sign-on widget like Facebook, Twitter or Google, or using a service like &lt;a href=&#34;janrain.com&#34;&gt;Janrain&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;gigya.com&#34;&gt;Gigya&lt;/a&gt;, you can ask for visitors to share additional information from their social profiles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;spyjax:86495ce0bd02ab48a50c4325d0c82ced&#34;&gt;SpyJax&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before leaving this session, I want to call out a crazy little trick I discovered a while back that has been dubbed &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidwalsh.name/ajax-evil-spyjax&#34;&gt;spyjax&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;. This is a technique that uses only javascript and css, taking advantage of the fact that browsers will make visited links a different color by default. Using Javascript, you can then read in if that color has been changed and discover what websites a user has been to. Now, you have to hardcode this list and it&amp;rsquo;s of limited value. It&amp;rsquo;s also an awful idea and a violation of privacy. It&amp;rsquo;s still a facinating little trick though.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 7: Agile Personalization Stories</title>
      <link>http://personalizationpodcast.com/post/episode-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2016 20:21:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://personalizationpodcast.com/post/episode-7/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;166&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/247755914&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;As a Marketer, I want to Personalize my site, so that I can better engage with my audience.&amp;rdquo; That&amp;rsquo;s an example of
how I might write an Agile Story about Personalization. In this episode we discuss the usefulness of stories in the
Agile process and also explore their direct relevance to helping us think about the right way to personalize by
focussing on the &amp;ldquo;who&amp;rdquo; and the &amp;ldquo;why&amp;rdquo; of what we&amp;rsquo;re doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-the-news:1520420b25182acb3bb29f38c6abc31d&#34;&gt;In the News&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;personalization-paradox-http-www-wunderman-emea-com-5-pointers-to-tackle-the-triple-personalization-paradox:1520420b25182acb3bb29f38c6abc31d&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wunderman-emea.com/5-pointers-to-tackle-the-triple-personalization-paradox&#34;&gt;Personalization Paradox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paradox #1. While paramount to cure the sheer saturation of inboxes and social feeds — see, for example, the Twitterverse’s recent ‘algorithm anxiety’ — &lt;strong&gt;personalization requires content in an even more vast variety to cater for individual needs and tastes.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paradox #2. The closer marketers get, it seems, the more likely they are to miss the mark: &lt;strong&gt;success recipes to ensure messages fall on the right ears at the right time definitely grow longer as conversations get more intimate.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paradox #3. Consumers seem to suffer from some sort of Catullus 85 Complex when it comes to personalization: they hate and they love personalization to a very similar extent: &lt;strong&gt;“39% of consumers say they get frustrated when retailers don’t offer personalized recommendations; 38% say the same about personalized offers.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personalization at its best is a problem solver, a relevant, tailored service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Content is probably the most often overlooked component of the “unified data ecosystem” enabling personalization.
A vital key to personalization success is, nonetheless, to be found in your CMS. If your messages are to be tailored
and meaningful in a one-to-one conversation, you are going to need a massive amount of them and they’ll have to
be tagged / calendared ex-ten-sive-ly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-your-organization-is-approaching-personalization-all-wrong-http-blogs-forrester-com-fiona-adler-16-01-12-why-your-organization-is-approaching-personalization-wrong:1520420b25182acb3bb29f38c6abc31d&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.forrester.com/fiona_adler/16-01-12-why_your_organization_is_approaching_personalization_wrong&#34;&gt;Why Your Organization is Approaching Personalization All Wrong&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;by Fiona Adler&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s in a name? Personalization vs. Individualization vs. Contextualization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ron Rogowski has &lt;a href=&#34;https://uxmag.com/articles/contextualization-is-the-key-to-delivering-powerful-personalized-digital-experiences&#34;&gt;written about contextualization vs. personalization&lt;/a&gt; as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firms that succeed with personalization are proactive and intentional about it.
They treat personalization as an enabler of better interactions from the
customers’ view across their journeys. Rather than contemplating, &amp;ldquo;How can
my organization implement personalization?&amp;rdquo; they ask, &amp;ldquo;What tasks and goals
are users trying to accomplish, and how can personalization enable users to
more seamlessly accomplish those?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;agile-stories:1520420b25182acb3bb29f38c6abc31d&#34;&gt;Agile Stories&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Format:&lt;/em&gt;
- Who - &amp;ldquo;As a&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;
- What - &amp;ldquo;I want&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;
- Why - &amp;ldquo;So that&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;As a shopper, I want to see product prices clearly labeled, so that I can find
something I know     is in my budget before I go to checkout.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;As a parent, I want my child to go to bed at night, so that I can relax.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;As a child, I want to wake up early in the morning, so that I can play.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;agile-personalization-stories:1520420b25182acb3bb29f38c6abc31d&#34;&gt;Agile Personalization Stories&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When writing stories for personalization, check the who and why closely. I can
write a story like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;As a Return Visitor, I want to see a message that says &amp;lsquo;welcome back!&amp;rsquo; so that
I can feel more appreciated.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watch out though. Do you actually know that this is the case? Do your return
visitors really want to be recognized as returning visitors? What if they feel
creeped out that you&amp;rsquo;re tracking them? This is a real concern and something that
may need to be addressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how do you deal with this? Research! If you don&amp;rsquo;t know for sure if your story
is true, then consider a more accurate story:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;As a Marketer, I want to test putting a &amp;lsquo;welcome back&amp;rsquo; message on the
home page for return visitors, so that I can determine whether they will (buy more,
stay longer, etc..)&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a research focussed story as opposed to a &amp;ldquo;just do it&amp;rdquo; story and it much
more accurately reflects our reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What about the &amp;ldquo;So What?&amp;rdquo; We can and will dedicate a few future episodes to talking
about Goal tracking and measurement, but this is where you can easily identify
the metric that you are trying to effect from creating this personalized experience.
This idea is absolutely critical, because if you&amp;rsquo;re not measuring something that
impacts your bottom line, then you have no idea whether your effort is paying
off or not. Always be very clear about what you&amp;rsquo;re measuring and why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice that the story format doesn&amp;rsquo;t address &amp;ldquo;how&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;when&amp;rdquo;. &amp;ldquo;How&amp;rdquo; should be
discussed, but when you&amp;rsquo;re trying to determine what will have the most effect
on your business or organization, asking who? what? and why? are your best
places to start.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Berndt, Part 2 - Personalization Vendors and measuring ROI</title>
      <link>http://personalizationpodcast.com/post/episode-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2016 20:27:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://personalizationpodcast.com/post/episode-6/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;john-berndt-part-2-personalization-vendors-and-measuring-roi:3680bfda9163c95344c39c81e2f28aa2&#34;&gt;John Berndt, Part 2 - Personalization Vendors and measuring ROI&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;166&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/246625142&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In part 2 of this Interview, John and I discuss personalization vendors and how to measure the Return on Investment (ROI) of a personalization program. John gives advice on picking the right software and breaks down some categories to help understand the space a little better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John Berndt is the CEO of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.berndtgroup.net/&#34;&gt;The Berndt Group&lt;/a&gt;, a national digital agency and leading Sitecore partner located in Baltimore Maryland, specializing in large web site design, personalization, and multi-channel with many large clients and household names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He is a 25-year digital veteran (1991) with experience on over 400 significant projects; also a national expert on content management systems, personalization, and digital operations. Last but not least, John is the author of a book called &amp;ldquo;Personalization Mechanics: Targeted Experience for Digital Teams of All Sizes.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe type=&#34;text/html&#34; width=&#34;336&#34; height=&#34;550&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen style=&#34;max-width:100%&#34; src=&#34;https://read.amazon.com/kp/card?asin=B00UKS4PYE&amp;preview=inline&amp;linkCode=kpe&amp;ref_=cm_sw_r_kb_dp_yH7Twb05MR4TK&#34; &gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Berndt: Personalization Mechanics, Part 1</title>
      <link>http://personalizationpodcast.com/post/episode-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2016 16:25:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://personalizationpodcast.com/post/episode-5/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;john-berndt-interview-part-1-personalization-mechanics:0a65935d03808cefb07e74a1babdf251&#34;&gt;John Berndt Interview, Part 1 - Personalization Mechanics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;166&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/245938357&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John Berndt is the CEO of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.berndtgroup.net/&#34;&gt;The Berndt Group&lt;/a&gt;, a national digital agency and leading Sitecore partner located in Baltimore Maryland, specializing in large web site design, personalization, and multi-channel with many large clients and household names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He is a 25-year digital veteran (1991) with experience on over 400 significant projects; also a national expert on content management systems, personalization, and digital operations. Last but not least, John is the author of a book called &amp;ldquo;Personalization Mechanics: Targeted Experience for Digital Teams of All Sizes.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John has been thinking and talking about Personalization for many years and helping large clients wrap their heads around what it takes to be successful with this technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among other things, we discuss in this episode John&amp;rsquo;s motivation for writing the book, what it takes to be successful with Personalization, who needs to be involved, what organizations should and shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be thinking about Personalization, and discuss some of the technology as well. John is the author of Personalization Mechanics linked here below (not an affiliate link or anything, just here for your convenience). It&amp;rsquo;s an excellent book and well worth the read if you are interested or working in this space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe type=&#34;text/html&#34; width=&#34;336&#34; height=&#34;550&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen style=&#34;max-width:100%&#34; src=&#34;https://read.amazon.com/kp/card?asin=B00UKS4PYE&amp;preview=inline&amp;linkCode=kpe&amp;ref_=cm_sw_r_kb_dp_yH7Twb05MR4TK&#34; &gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 4: Kyle Polich, Data Skepticism in Personalization</title>
      <link>http://personalizationpodcast.com/post/episode-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2016 22:00:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://personalizationpodcast.com/post/episode-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;166&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/245513568&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this show I&amp;rsquo;m joined by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dataskeptic&#34;&gt;Kyle Polich&lt;/a&gt;  of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://dataskeptic.com/&#34;&gt;Data Skeptic Podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kyle and I discuss the importance of being skeptical of and with data, within the context of Personalization, Web Analytics and particularly A/B testing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resources mentioned in this show:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.openintro.org/stat/textbook.php&#34;&gt;Open Intro Statistics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/BecomingDataSci&#34;&gt;Data Science Renee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 3: Agile Personalization Explained</title>
      <link>http://personalizationpodcast.com/post/episode-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 21:55:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://personalizationpodcast.com/post/episode-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;166&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/242024170&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello and welcome to The Personalization Podcast! This is the show about
understanding, planning, building and analyzing personalized experiences.
I&amp;rsquo;m your host, Dave Ingram, and today we&amp;rsquo;re going to be talking about Agile
Personalization, or in other words, how you can get the most out of a
personalization program and a personalization team in the least amount of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doing personalization well is all about iterating quickly, and that&amp;rsquo;s what
this episode is about. We&amp;rsquo;ll be borrowing a lot of ideas from the software
development space, but FEAR NOT! There&amp;rsquo;s no deep, technical stuff coming
your way. These are straight forward, down to earth principles that you can
take and apply to almost any area of your life or business that needs to
be more efficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t forget, you can get to show notes at personalizationpodcast.com, and
you can send questions and feedback to @p13npodcast on Twitter or the
Personalization Podcast page on Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-the-news:cb51fda0943db036025e1dcca5e429a3&#34;&gt;In the News&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;smart-refrigerators-http-www-cnet-com-news-touchscreen-refrigerators-and-talking-everything-at-ces-2016:cb51fda0943db036025e1dcca5e429a3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cnet.com/news/touchscreen-refrigerators-and-talking-everything-at-ces-2016/&#34;&gt;Smart Refrigerators?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve heard about them for years, and there was a new one revealed last week
at CES. It&amp;rsquo;s got a pretty big touch screen that will run apps so you can look
up recipes just like people have been saying for a long time. Maybe no big deal,
but one feature that I like is that it will actually send you pictures of what&amp;rsquo;s
inside your fridge when you&amp;rsquo;re at the store so you can see what you forgot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worth the $5000 price tag? probably not, but neat none the less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does this have to do with personalization? Well, CES was full of all the
other hot new gadgets from wearables to connected homes to self driving cars
which should give anyone pause who is thinking in terms of the Web and Email
only. The world is changing quickly, and if you&amp;rsquo;re creating digital experiences,
you need to be prepared for it all to be different very soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;9-reasons-why-personalized-marketing-still-isn-t-accurate-http-www-informationweek-com-big-data-big-data-analytics-9-reasons-why-personalized-marketing-still-isnt-accurate-d-d-id-1323736-image-number-2:cb51fda0943db036025e1dcca5e429a3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.informationweek.com/big-data/big-data-analytics/9-reasons-why-personalized-marketing-still-isnt-accurate/d/d-id/1323736?image_number=2&#34;&gt;9 Reasons Why Personalized Marketing Still Isn&amp;rsquo;t Accurate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Information Week - Lisa Morgan&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Data Quality Is Poor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data Isn&amp;rsquo;t Integrated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re relying too heavily on Legacy Systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re discounting internal data assets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re putting too much faith in the wrong data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The analytics used are too basic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re relying too much on technology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You think personalization is a marketing problem &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;customers expect personalized experiences throughout the lifetime of a relationship with a company&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Still Early Days &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;While there&amp;rsquo;s a debate about the maturity state of the technology, what&amp;rsquo;s less debated is the need for organizational change.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;agile-personalization:cb51fda0943db036025e1dcca5e429a3&#34;&gt;Agile Personalization&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;key-ideas:cb51fda0943db036025e1dcca5e429a3&#34;&gt;Key ideas:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Iteration and Learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Infinite possibilities when it comes to things you can do&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strategy, Goals and Initiatives .. high level and we&amp;rsquo;ll come back to this&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tasks or Stories

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where do Stories come from?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prioritization of Stories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sprints or Iterations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also mentioned Facebook Planout, an open source experimentation framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all of these ideas in written form, look out for a soon to be published
blog post on &lt;a href=&#34;http://acquia.com&#34;&gt;Acquia.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 2: The Personalization Team</title>
      <link>http://personalizationpodcast.com/post/episode-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 21:53:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://personalizationpodcast.com/post/episode-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;166&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/241498057&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Episode 2 of The Personalization Podcast&amp;ndash;The show about understanding,
planning, building and analyzing Personalized Experiences. We talked last time
about what personalization is, so today we&amp;rsquo;re going to talk about the very first
step you need to take to get started. This doesn&amp;rsquo;t involve buying software,
building complex infrastructure or anything of that sort. Step 1 is all about
People. In fact, thinking about what it takes to be successful in personalization,
I think there are three things that matter: People, Process and Product. The
software itself is last in line because if you don&amp;rsquo;t have the right people and
an appropriate process in place, you&amp;rsquo;ll be set up for failure no matter how
much you spend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we dive into the news, in the last episode I promised a Q&amp;amp;A section, but
never gave a method to reach out. So if you want to ask questions, send feedback
or just generally get in touch, you can go to personalizationpodcast.com, or
tweet to @p13npodcast. P13n is an abbreviation for Personalization. In other words,
there&amp;rsquo;s a p, 13 more letters, then an n. It turns out personalizationpodcast is
too long for a twitter handle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case Twitter isn&amp;rsquo;t your thing. You can also find the show on facebook by
simply searching for Personalization Podcast and post questions or feedback
there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-the-news:51ade350eab725e837a47d1a4253ca0c&#34;&gt;In the News&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-contextual-marketing-imperative-http-go-sap-com-docs-download-2015-10-3c6868f1-487c-0010-82c7-eda71af511fa-pdf:51ade350eab725e837a47d1a4253ca0c&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://go.sap.com/docs/download/2015/10/3c6868f1-487c-0010-82c7-eda71af511fa.pdf&#34;&gt;The Contextual Marketing Imperative&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This paper came across my Twitter feed the other day, and while it was published
in October last year, it still seems worth sharing. In fact, it was &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.websitemagazine.com/content/blogs/posts/archive/2016/01/08/the-time-is-now-personalization-in-the-age-of-contextual-marketing.aspx&#34;&gt;an  infographic&lt;/a&gt; which had initially caught
my eye, which has a number of interesting statistics about personalization based
on the Forrester Survey. Some key stats follow:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;91% of marketers are prioritizing improving customer experience through personalization
over the next year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;66% of consumers reported that personalized offers and content has had an impact on their
decision to purchase a product or service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;44% of customers say they receive too many offers and promotions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marketers use an average of 15 siloed data sources, resulting in inconsistent
customer experiences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;algorithms-need-managers-too-https-hbr-org-2016-01-algorithms-need-managers-too:51ade350eab725e837a47d1a4253ca0c&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hbr.org/2016/01/algorithms-need-managers-too&#34;&gt;Algorithms need Managers, Too&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Algorithms get things wrong and need management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Defining your goals correctly is one of the most important things that you can do, as this story illustrates:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Everyone has objectives and directives, but we also know that the end doesn’t always justify the means. We understand that there are soft (often unspoken) goals and trade-offs. We may turn down a little profit today for a gain in reputation tomorrow. We may strive for equality—even if it causes organizational pain in the short term. Algorithms, on the other hand, will pursue a specified objective single-mindedly. The best way to mitigate this is to be crystal clear about everything you want to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you care about a soft goal, you need to state it, define it, and quantify how much it matters. To the extent that soft goals are difficult to measure, keep them top of mind when acting on the results from an algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Google (which has funded some of our research on other topics), a soft-goal problem emerged with an algorithm that determines which ads to display. Harvard professor Latanya Sweeney unearthed it in a study. She found that when you typed names that were typically African American, like “Latanya Farrell,” into Google, you were shown ads offering to investigate possible arrest records, but not when you searched on names like “Kristen Haring.” Google’s hard goal of maximizing clicks on ads had led to a situation in which its algorithms, refined through feedback over time, were in effect defaming people with certain kinds of names. It happened because people who searched for particular names were more likely to click on arrest records, which led these records to appear even more often, creating a self-reinforcing loop. This probably was not the intended outcome, but without a soft goal in place, there was no mechanism to steer the algorithm away from it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-personalization-team:51ade350eab725e837a47d1a4253ca0c&#34;&gt;The Personalization Team&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;skills-required:51ade350eab725e837a47d1a4253ca0c&#34;&gt;Skills Required&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Creatives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Analysts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Technical&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Personalization Owner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This should be a Cross Functional team as much as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s fine if some of these people are from agencies, but the key point is that
you need to be iterative. Without iteration, you won&amp;rsquo;t see benefits quickly
enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this section in full written form, check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.acquia.com/blog/how-build-successful-personalization-team/06/01/2016/3291021&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;
on this topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;learning-from-agile:51ade350eab725e837a47d1a4253ca0c&#34;&gt;Learning from Agile&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next episode I&amp;rsquo;ll do a breakdown of what Agile Personalization is really all about,
but the preview for today is that being Agile means iterating quickly over a lot
of ideas and properly prioritizing those ideas so that you&amp;rsquo;re doing the best
things first. On top of that, you see results quickly. Quick results mean happy
stakeholders and more success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A couple of reading suggestions:&lt;/em&gt;
- &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/The-Lean-Startup-Entrepreneurs-Continuous/dp/0307887898&#34;&gt;Lean Startup by Eric Ries&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Scrum-Doing-Twice-Work-Half/dp/038534645X&#34;&gt;Scrum by Jeff Sutherland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-of-the-week:51ade350eab725e837a47d1a4253ca0c&#34;&gt;Tip of the Week&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Free A/B testing! Google has A/B testing baked into Google Analytics. If you&amp;rsquo;re
looking to get a quick start into Personalization and don&amp;rsquo;t have the budget for
advanced software, check this out. It&amp;rsquo;s called &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/1745152?hl=en&#34;&gt;Content Experiments&lt;/a&gt; and it
allows you to direct people to 2 or more different URLs and see how they respond
to each.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 1: Welcome and What is Personalization?</title>
      <link>http://personalizationpodcast.com/post/episode-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 21:51:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://personalizationpodcast.com/post/episode-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;166&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/240912763&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello and welcome to the Personalization Podcast, the show about understanding, planning, creating and analyzing personalized experiences. I am your host, Dave Ingram, and I am excited to bring you this first of many episodes! Today’s show is all about defining personalization. What is it? What can you do with it? What all is involved?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll also be talking a little bit about the format of this show and what you can expect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might also be wondering who this guy is who’s talking to you right now, so a very brief introduction. I grew up in the South, then moved to New England to be involved in building a personalization product called Acquia Lift. This show isn’t going to talk much about that product, though I may slip in an anecdote or example from it from time to time. In college I pursued degrees in music and computer science before eventually settling on political science, after which I promptly went to work in the tech field building websites. I’ve subsequently worked in both sales and in product management. I have hobbies in music and photography.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could either say that I’m interested in lots of subjects, or that I have a hard time keeping interest in one thing for long enough. In either case, hat’s probably why I’m so fascinated in the subject of Personalization which sits at the intersection of technology and the humanities, encompassing subjects as diverse as data science and machine learning, several branches of psychology, organizational structure and management, big data challenges, and various other technical and non-technical subjects. Many of these areas are also changing rapidly, so just trying to keep up can be an enormous challenge. So this show is going to cover pretty much anything that I feel is related in any meaningful way to building personalized experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some episodes will be just me, covering a specific topic in personalization such as building personalization teams and process ideas on how to run them, as well as tools and techniques available for doing personalization. In other episodes, I’ll be bringing on guests to talk about, again, pretty much anything related in any way to personalization, so look for experts in marketing, technology, data science, user experience research, psychology and more as the weeks roll on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to whatever the main section is, we’ll also be starting out each show with a quick look into the news to bring both breaking stories, as pointing you to other great articles, books or podcasts in this space. Then, at the end of each episode, we’ll reserve a few minutes for either a question and answer or for a Tip of the Week. Just one more little nugget until we meet again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, whether you’re building personalized experiences yourself, working with or managing someone who is, or just interested in where this field is going, I’m excited about this journey and I hope you’ll join me along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-the-news:2fede85e9f1a69a5f89f1b281051b3fc&#34;&gt;In the News&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2016-five-predictions-for-the-conversion-optimization-industry-http-conversion-com-blog-2016-five-predictions-for-the-conversion-optimization-industry:2fede85e9f1a69a5f89f1b281051b3fc&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://conversion.com/blog/2016-five-predictions-for-the-conversion-optimization-industry/&#34;&gt;2016: Five predictions for the conversion optimization industry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stephen Pavlovich&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I have a love/hate relationship with personalization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It offers a huge opportunity to companies with a strong foundation of split-testing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if you don’t have this foundation – if you don’t know which user segments to target, what motivates them and what stops them – then you risk forking your website and creating multiple suboptimal experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But personalization can and should be huge – both for brands and the software vendors that support them.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;digital-personalization-separating-hype-from-reality-https-medium-com-blatantdigital-digital-personalization-separating-hype-from-reality-889e082ee53d-fo055nk8q:2fede85e9f1a69a5f89f1b281051b3fc&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@BlatantDigital/digital-personalization-separating-hype-from-reality-889e082ee53d#.fo055nk8q&#34;&gt;Digital Personalization, Separating Hype from Reality&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;How many companies out there mega million dollar budgets with teams of engineers and statisticians running experiments on details like the color or shape of a button? How many companies are selling consumer-specific products at towering scale? These case studies [about Amazon and Netflix] are not relevant for most businesses.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Responsible Marketer’s Quick Start Guide to Personalization
1. Research your audience.
2. Develop Useful Segments and Personas.
3. Create Customer Journey Maps.
4. Identify Meaningful KPIs.
5. Produce Kickass Content.
6. Run Controlled Experiments.
7. Personalize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-personalization:2fede85e9f1a69a5f89f1b281051b3fc&#34;&gt;What is Personalization?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let’s take a moment to define what we actually mean by personalization. There are a few possible definitions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Showing the right content, to the right person, at the right time
Guiding an individual’s experience based on their context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either one of these works, but I like the latter. To me, the concept of personalization is really quite simple. If I know something about you that might be relevant to help me serve your needs better, then I will use that piece of information to guide you in the right direction. An example based on retail stores is in the episode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contextualization vs. Personalization: semantics in my opinion but there&amp;rsquo;s some great research there that&amp;rsquo;s worth looking at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-context-is-available:2fede85e9f1a69a5f89f1b281051b3fc&#34;&gt;What context is available?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask them a question&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Device&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Geography&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Referral Source&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Behavior&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a lot in all of this, and we&amp;rsquo;ll be exploring this more in future episodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-do-you-respond-to-that-context:2fede85e9f1a69a5f89f1b281051b3fc&#34;&gt;How do you respond to that context?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use either Rules or Algorithms. Lots of software available. More on specific techniques in future episodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-importance-of-testing:2fede85e9f1a69a5f89f1b281051b3fc&#34;&gt;The importance of testing.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A/B testing is absolutely critical. If you don’t test, you’re wasting a lot of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-of-the-week:2fede85e9f1a69a5f89f1b281051b3fc&#34;&gt;Tip of the Week&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think like a scientist. Become a researcher and search for generalizable knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;thanks:2fede85e9f1a69a5f89f1b281051b3fc&#34;&gt;Thanks!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://personalizationpodcast.com&#34;&gt;personalizationpodcast.com&lt;/a&gt; to view show notes and to send questions and feedback. And stay tuned for the next episode where we’ll dive into building a personalization team and talk about using an agile process to reap the benefits of personalization as early as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>