<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personalization on The Personalization Podcast</title>
    <link>http://personalizationpodcast.com/tags/personalization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personalization on The Personalization Podcast</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2016 12:21:07 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://personalizationpodcast.com/tags/personalization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 8: Context, Context, Context</title>
      <link>http://personalizationpodcast.com/post/episode-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2016 12:21:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://personalizationpodcast.com/post/episode-8/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;context-context-context:86495ce0bd02ab48a50c4325d0c82ced&#34;&gt;Context, Context, Context&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;166&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/248948406&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Content is King, then Context is Queen. Personalization is all about matching
the right content or messaging to the right person, and doing that means you need
to know something about who that person is. In fact, the more you know, the more
likely you are to be successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s not to say that all context is created equal though. Depending on your
organization and your audience, different pieces of information may be critical
or close to meaningless. As a simple example, a retailer may be heavily effected
by a customer&amp;rsquo;s local weather. Cold and rainy, you may need a rain coat. Warm and
Sunny? Time for the beach!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s episode is all about cataloging the &lt;em&gt;kinds of things&lt;/em&gt; that we can know
about the consumers of our digital experiences. The list is quite broad and it
will range from the fairly straight forward and obvious, into perhaps surprising
and sometimes creepy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But first, let&amp;rsquo;s look at the news to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-s-news-to-me:86495ce0bd02ab48a50c4325d0c82ced&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s News to Me&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;etail-west-and-browser-push-notifications:86495ce0bd02ab48a50c4325d0c82ced&#34;&gt;eTail West and Browser Push Notifications&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personalization has been an important strategy for retailers longer than for anyone else. In many ways, Amazon was the original pioneer of personalization with their early product recommendations, and many sellers and personalization vendors have latched onto that idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, &lt;a href=&#34;http://etailwest.wbresearch.com/&#34;&gt;eTail West&lt;/a&gt; is just wrapping up this week, and many sessions focussed on data, omni-channel, personalization and related topics. Before looking at an interesting case study though, I came across a request on eTail&amp;rsquo;s website to subscribe for push notifications. The only place I&amp;rsquo;d seen this before was Facebook, but in case you didn&amp;rsquo;t know, it&amp;rsquo;s now possible to send push notifications directly through a browser. This has generally just been the realm of mobile applications, so this opens up some interesting doors for marketers, though I&amp;rsquo;m not convinced it will really catch on yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, I signed up for the same vendor eTail is using, which is called &lt;a href=&#34;https://pushcrew.com/&#34;&gt;PushCrew&lt;/a&gt;, and have put it up on personalizationpodcast.com at least temporarily to try it out. You can go there and have a look if you&amp;rsquo;re interested. I don&amp;rsquo;t see any capabilities for targeting or personalizing push notifications at the moment, but clearly it would be possible to do this and may be of great interest to some of you out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-sephora-pairs-individual-loyalty-data-to-optimize-segmentation-http-www-luxurydaily-com-how-sephora-pairs-individual-loyalty-data-to-optimize-segmentation:86495ce0bd02ab48a50c4325d0c82ced&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.luxurydaily.com/how-sephora-pairs-individual-loyalty-data-to-optimize-segmentation/&#34;&gt;How Sephora pairs individual, loyalty data to optimize segmentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By Alex Samuely&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“[Data] is kind of a currency to us,” said Angel Singh, director of product
analytics and optimization at Sephora. “We have a lot of data on our clients
and we’re trying to figure out how to leverage it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data is imperative when it comes to pinpointing how best to target consumers, since many of them complete shopping journeys across multiple devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When we think about our clients, we know that they don’t just go into the store and buy something,” Ms. Singh said. “There is a journey.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twenty-three percent of shoppers compare prices on mobile while standing in-store and before going to a bricks-and-mortar location. Additionally, 24 percent engage with a retail app each week, leaving a prime opportunity for marketers to connect with loyal customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sephora has extended its omnichannel reach to include optimized emails, a new subscription box, a mobile app and mobile Web site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The brand also offers a popular loyalty program, Beauty Insider, which rewards users with points for each dollar spent. Points can then be redeemed for sample-size products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we come to the clincher:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sephora is focusing on digging up real-time data, which has previously proven to be a trickier process due to silos. Having access to individual data would help the brand – as well as in-store associates – give shoppers a personalized experience based on their &lt;em&gt;skin types, beauty regimes and past purchases.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We want to recognize everybody,” Ms. Singh said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pull that quote specifically because it captures the point of this episode: Context. Sephora wants to know who people are, and for them that means some very specific things. For your organization, it will certainly be different, but narrowing down which variables matter is the key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;all-about-context:86495ce0bd02ab48a50c4325d0c82ced&#34;&gt;All about Context&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what can you know about your visitors? It turns out that it&amp;rsquo;s really quite a lot. We&amp;rsquo;re going to start by looking at the raw materials, and work outward to see what can be learned based on that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, let&amp;rsquo;s start with a simple HTTP header which may look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;GET /tutorials/other/top-20-mysql-best-practices/ HTTP/1.1
Host: net.tutsplus.com
User-Agent: Mozilla/5.0 (Windows; U; Windows NT 6.1; en-US; rv:1.9.1.5) Gecko/20091102 Firefox/3.5.5 (.NET CLR 3.5.30729)
Accept: text/html,application/xhtml+xml,application/xml;q=0.9,*/*;q=0.8
Accept-Language: en-us,en;q=0.5
Accept-Encoding: gzip,deflate
Accept-Charset: ISO-8859-1,utf-8;q=0.7,*;q=0.7
Referer: https://www.google.com
Keep-Alive: 300
Connection: keep-alive
Cookie: PHPSESSID=r2t5uvjq435r4q7ib3vtdjq120
Pragma: no-cache
Cache-Control: no-cache
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(source: &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.tutsplus.com/tutorials/http-headers-for-dummies--net-8039&#34;&gt;tutsplus.com tutorial&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From this very simple request header, the spec for which was last edited in 1994, we can learn an awful lot:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;user-agent:86495ce0bd02ab48a50c4325d0c82ced&#34;&gt;User Agent&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This short line of text can be hard to read, but thankfully others have done the hard work of being able to do this, and by running this text through various services such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://uadetector.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;UA Detector&lt;/a&gt;, we can learn things like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browser Version&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Device&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Operating System&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;accept-language:86495ce0bd02ab48a50c4325d0c82ced&#34;&gt;Accept-Language&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What language has the visitor set their browser for? This is a great source of information for what they may prefer and allows you to give them content in that language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;referrer:86495ce0bd02ab48a50c4325d0c82ced&#34;&gt;Referrer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where did they come from? Search Engine? Social Media? Another page on your site? An Ad?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of the page they came from, you can also look at parameters in the url such as Campaign and Source, which are often used by analytics, but can also be used for personalization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;cookies:86495ce0bd02ab48a50c4325d0c82ced&#34;&gt;Cookies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First and 3rd party cookies are also passed in here. Cookies are how the browser and the server maintain &amp;ldquo;state&amp;rdquo;, which means that the server can recognize the same person from page to page. This becomes incredibly important in a moment when we talk about behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ip-address:86495ce0bd02ab48a50c4325d0c82ced&#34;&gt;IP address&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While not always in the headers, we have IP addresses available from the request itself. While the IP Address itself may look like just numbers, we can use it to infer, with relatively good accuracy, the geographic location of the visitor using a database such as the one from Maxmind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.maxmind.com/en/locate-my-ip-address&#34;&gt;test it for yourself to see how it does&lt;/a&gt;. For me it nailed my postal code, city and state. It also returned a latitude and longitude, but missed me by about 5 miles. This is because it&amp;rsquo;s the lat/long for the zip code and no closer, so you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t expect huge precision from this method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other services, such as &lt;a href=&#34;demandbase.com&#34;&gt;Demandbase&lt;/a&gt; build databases of IP addresses for organizations and can determine what company is viewing this page, giving you access to information like Company Name, company size, industry, number of employees and more. This &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt; for B2B companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;geography:86495ce0bd02ab48a50c4325d0c82ced&#34;&gt;Geography&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of geolocation, we can also ask the visitor to share their more precise location. This is often done in mobile applications, but can be done on the desktop as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;past-behavior:86495ce0bd02ab48a50c4325d0c82ced&#34;&gt;Past Behavior&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By keeping track of who we&amp;rsquo;ve seen and what they did, now we can build up a picture of who this person is and what they&amp;rsquo;re really looking for. This may well be the holy grail of context for the majority of organizations, but is also considerably more difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Future episodes will discuss machine learning and how this can be applied, but simpler rules based approaches can also be extremely valuable. For example, if a visitor has already bought one product, you can stop showing them that product and show others that are of interest. If they&amp;rsquo;ve spent most of their time on a particular topic on a news site, you might show them more news from that subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-if-cookies-get-cleared:86495ce0bd02ab48a50c4325d0c82ced&#34;&gt;What if Cookies get cleared?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually if someone clears their cookies, if they come to your site again they will look like a brand new user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A variety of technology exists to try to get around this, generally referred to as &amp;ldquo;device fingerprinting&amp;rdquo;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Device_fingerprint&#34;&gt;The Wikipedia page for Device Fingerprinting&lt;/a&gt; does a good job of explaining what it is and the privacy violation risks. That&amp;rsquo;s going to be a topic of a future episode, but for the time being, think twice before doing something like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ask-them-questions:86495ce0bd02ab48a50c4325d0c82ced&#34;&gt;Ask them questions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything above is basically &amp;ldquo;inferred&amp;rdquo; information from what you see a visitor do. You can also just ask them. This is generally done when a user registers for a site and needs to fill in things like name, email address, age, etc. You can also employ the technique of &amp;ldquo;progressive profiling&amp;rdquo;, which means you ask for a little more information each time. LinkedIn is very good at this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also effectively ask questions without requiring a log in. One great example is by providing links in a navigation structure which request that someone identify which type of customer they are. This can then be captured and as long as you still have that visitor cookied, you can remember their selection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;behavior-off-site:86495ce0bd02ab48a50c4325d0c82ced&#34;&gt;Behavior Off-site&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;3rd-party-cookies:86495ce0bd02ab48a50c4325d0c82ced&#34;&gt;3rd Party Cookies&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.oracle.com/cloud/latest/marketingcs_gs/OMCDA/pdf/Misc/bluekai-little-blue-book.pdf&#34;&gt;Little Blue Book&lt;/a&gt; provides an extensive encylopedia of data sources that can be tapped into, largely focussed on 3rd party advertising cookies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These can be great, but beward 3rd party cookie decline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;social-mining:86495ce0bd02ab48a50c4325d0c82ced&#34;&gt;Social Mining&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example company is &lt;a href=&#34;clearbit.com&#34;&gt;Clearbit&lt;/a&gt;. Go there and type in your email address and see what you get. For me it accurately nailed my website, company, twitter handle, as well as information about my company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://personalizationpodcast.com/images/clearbit.png&#34; alt=&#34;Clearbit Data Lookup&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s more, from knowing my twitter handle, one could go and look at my past tweets, who I follow, what I like and dislike (at least, what I&amp;rsquo;ve shared on twitter.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This whole area of social mining is a huge field and there&amp;rsquo;s much more depth possible there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;social-sign-on:86495ce0bd02ab48a50c4325d0c82ced&#34;&gt;Social Sign-on&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides the public facing data available from sites like Facebook and Twitter, if you ask a customer to sign on using a social sign-on widget like Facebook, Twitter or Google, or using a service like &lt;a href=&#34;janrain.com&#34;&gt;Janrain&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;gigya.com&#34;&gt;Gigya&lt;/a&gt;, you can ask for visitors to share additional information from their social profiles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;spyjax:86495ce0bd02ab48a50c4325d0c82ced&#34;&gt;SpyJax&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before leaving this session, I want to call out a crazy little trick I discovered a while back that has been dubbed &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidwalsh.name/ajax-evil-spyjax&#34;&gt;spyjax&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;. This is a technique that uses only javascript and css, taking advantage of the fact that browsers will make visited links a different color by default. Using Javascript, you can then read in if that color has been changed and discover what websites a user has been to. Now, you have to hardcode this list and it&amp;rsquo;s of limited value. It&amp;rsquo;s also an awful idea and a violation of privacy. It&amp;rsquo;s still a facinating little trick though.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Berndt, Part 2 - Personalization Vendors and measuring ROI</title>
      <link>http://personalizationpodcast.com/post/episode-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2016 20:27:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://personalizationpodcast.com/post/episode-6/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;john-berndt-part-2-personalization-vendors-and-measuring-roi:3680bfda9163c95344c39c81e2f28aa2&#34;&gt;John Berndt, Part 2 - Personalization Vendors and measuring ROI&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;166&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/246625142&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In part 2 of this Interview, John and I discuss personalization vendors and how to measure the Return on Investment (ROI) of a personalization program. John gives advice on picking the right software and breaks down some categories to help understand the space a little better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John Berndt is the CEO of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.berndtgroup.net/&#34;&gt;The Berndt Group&lt;/a&gt;, a national digital agency and leading Sitecore partner located in Baltimore Maryland, specializing in large web site design, personalization, and multi-channel with many large clients and household names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He is a 25-year digital veteran (1991) with experience on over 400 significant projects; also a national expert on content management systems, personalization, and digital operations. Last but not least, John is the author of a book called &amp;ldquo;Personalization Mechanics: Targeted Experience for Digital Teams of All Sizes.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe type=&#34;text/html&#34; width=&#34;336&#34; height=&#34;550&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen style=&#34;max-width:100%&#34; src=&#34;https://read.amazon.com/kp/card?asin=B00UKS4PYE&amp;preview=inline&amp;linkCode=kpe&amp;ref_=cm_sw_r_kb_dp_yH7Twb05MR4TK&#34; &gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Berndt: Personalization Mechanics, Part 1</title>
      <link>http://personalizationpodcast.com/post/episode-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2016 16:25:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://personalizationpodcast.com/post/episode-5/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;john-berndt-interview-part-1-personalization-mechanics:0a65935d03808cefb07e74a1babdf251&#34;&gt;John Berndt Interview, Part 1 - Personalization Mechanics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;166&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/245938357&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John Berndt is the CEO of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.berndtgroup.net/&#34;&gt;The Berndt Group&lt;/a&gt;, a national digital agency and leading Sitecore partner located in Baltimore Maryland, specializing in large web site design, personalization, and multi-channel with many large clients and household names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He is a 25-year digital veteran (1991) with experience on over 400 significant projects; also a national expert on content management systems, personalization, and digital operations. Last but not least, John is the author of a book called &amp;ldquo;Personalization Mechanics: Targeted Experience for Digital Teams of All Sizes.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John has been thinking and talking about Personalization for many years and helping large clients wrap their heads around what it takes to be successful with this technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among other things, we discuss in this episode John&amp;rsquo;s motivation for writing the book, what it takes to be successful with Personalization, who needs to be involved, what organizations should and shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be thinking about Personalization, and discuss some of the technology as well. John is the author of Personalization Mechanics linked here below (not an affiliate link or anything, just here for your convenience). It&amp;rsquo;s an excellent book and well worth the read if you are interested or working in this space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe type=&#34;text/html&#34; width=&#34;336&#34; height=&#34;550&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen style=&#34;max-width:100%&#34; src=&#34;https://read.amazon.com/kp/card?asin=B00UKS4PYE&amp;preview=inline&amp;linkCode=kpe&amp;ref_=cm_sw_r_kb_dp_yH7Twb05MR4TK&#34; &gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 1: Welcome and What is Personalization?</title>
      <link>http://personalizationpodcast.com/post/episode-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 21:51:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://personalizationpodcast.com/post/episode-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;166&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/240912763&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello and welcome to the Personalization Podcast, the show about understanding, planning, creating and analyzing personalized experiences. I am your host, Dave Ingram, and I am excited to bring you this first of many episodes! Today’s show is all about defining personalization. What is it? What can you do with it? What all is involved?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll also be talking a little bit about the format of this show and what you can expect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might also be wondering who this guy is who’s talking to you right now, so a very brief introduction. I grew up in the South, then moved to New England to be involved in building a personalization product called Acquia Lift. This show isn’t going to talk much about that product, though I may slip in an anecdote or example from it from time to time. In college I pursued degrees in music and computer science before eventually settling on political science, after which I promptly went to work in the tech field building websites. I’ve subsequently worked in both sales and in product management. I have hobbies in music and photography.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could either say that I’m interested in lots of subjects, or that I have a hard time keeping interest in one thing for long enough. In either case, hat’s probably why I’m so fascinated in the subject of Personalization which sits at the intersection of technology and the humanities, encompassing subjects as diverse as data science and machine learning, several branches of psychology, organizational structure and management, big data challenges, and various other technical and non-technical subjects. Many of these areas are also changing rapidly, so just trying to keep up can be an enormous challenge. So this show is going to cover pretty much anything that I feel is related in any meaningful way to building personalized experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some episodes will be just me, covering a specific topic in personalization such as building personalization teams and process ideas on how to run them, as well as tools and techniques available for doing personalization. In other episodes, I’ll be bringing on guests to talk about, again, pretty much anything related in any way to personalization, so look for experts in marketing, technology, data science, user experience research, psychology and more as the weeks roll on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to whatever the main section is, we’ll also be starting out each show with a quick look into the news to bring both breaking stories, as pointing you to other great articles, books or podcasts in this space. Then, at the end of each episode, we’ll reserve a few minutes for either a question and answer or for a Tip of the Week. Just one more little nugget until we meet again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, whether you’re building personalized experiences yourself, working with or managing someone who is, or just interested in where this field is going, I’m excited about this journey and I hope you’ll join me along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-the-news:2fede85e9f1a69a5f89f1b281051b3fc&#34;&gt;In the News&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2016-five-predictions-for-the-conversion-optimization-industry-http-conversion-com-blog-2016-five-predictions-for-the-conversion-optimization-industry:2fede85e9f1a69a5f89f1b281051b3fc&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://conversion.com/blog/2016-five-predictions-for-the-conversion-optimization-industry/&#34;&gt;2016: Five predictions for the conversion optimization industry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stephen Pavlovich&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I have a love/hate relationship with personalization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It offers a huge opportunity to companies with a strong foundation of split-testing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if you don’t have this foundation – if you don’t know which user segments to target, what motivates them and what stops them – then you risk forking your website and creating multiple suboptimal experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But personalization can and should be huge – both for brands and the software vendors that support them.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;digital-personalization-separating-hype-from-reality-https-medium-com-blatantdigital-digital-personalization-separating-hype-from-reality-889e082ee53d-fo055nk8q:2fede85e9f1a69a5f89f1b281051b3fc&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@BlatantDigital/digital-personalization-separating-hype-from-reality-889e082ee53d#.fo055nk8q&#34;&gt;Digital Personalization, Separating Hype from Reality&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;How many companies out there mega million dollar budgets with teams of engineers and statisticians running experiments on details like the color or shape of a button? How many companies are selling consumer-specific products at towering scale? These case studies [about Amazon and Netflix] are not relevant for most businesses.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Responsible Marketer’s Quick Start Guide to Personalization
1. Research your audience.
2. Develop Useful Segments and Personas.
3. Create Customer Journey Maps.
4. Identify Meaningful KPIs.
5. Produce Kickass Content.
6. Run Controlled Experiments.
7. Personalize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-personalization:2fede85e9f1a69a5f89f1b281051b3fc&#34;&gt;What is Personalization?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let’s take a moment to define what we actually mean by personalization. There are a few possible definitions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Showing the right content, to the right person, at the right time
Guiding an individual’s experience based on their context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either one of these works, but I like the latter. To me, the concept of personalization is really quite simple. If I know something about you that might be relevant to help me serve your needs better, then I will use that piece of information to guide you in the right direction. An example based on retail stores is in the episode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contextualization vs. Personalization: semantics in my opinion but there&amp;rsquo;s some great research there that&amp;rsquo;s worth looking at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-context-is-available:2fede85e9f1a69a5f89f1b281051b3fc&#34;&gt;What context is available?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask them a question&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Device&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Geography&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Referral Source&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Behavior&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a lot in all of this, and we&amp;rsquo;ll be exploring this more in future episodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-do-you-respond-to-that-context:2fede85e9f1a69a5f89f1b281051b3fc&#34;&gt;How do you respond to that context?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use either Rules or Algorithms. Lots of software available. More on specific techniques in future episodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-importance-of-testing:2fede85e9f1a69a5f89f1b281051b3fc&#34;&gt;The importance of testing.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A/B testing is absolutely critical. If you don’t test, you’re wasting a lot of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-of-the-week:2fede85e9f1a69a5f89f1b281051b3fc&#34;&gt;Tip of the Week&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think like a scientist. Become a researcher and search for generalizable knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;thanks:2fede85e9f1a69a5f89f1b281051b3fc&#34;&gt;Thanks!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://personalizationpodcast.com&#34;&gt;personalizationpodcast.com&lt;/a&gt; to view show notes and to send questions and feedback. And stay tuned for the next episode where we’ll dive into building a personalization team and talk about using an agile process to reap the benefits of personalization as early as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>